This is Trigun.
Oh, my God.
Meryl, look!
Meryl?
Meryl, wake up!
Oh, um...
Oh, hi, Karen.
Interesting.
I'm sorry.
Did you enjoy your rest?
I've been traveling around for so long,
I guess I haven't quite
regained my land legs yet.
It must be strange to be home.
After all, Miss Strife, you witnessed the
hole being burned into the fifth moon.
How did it make you
feel when you looked up?
This is not some tourist interview, Mark.
Stop it.
You're talking to someone who
spent five months on the outside,
working with the ultra-dangerous man
who's been labeled a human disaster.
Considering everything that's
happened to her out there,
It's a miracle that she came back alive.
Yes, but...
Actually, it wasn't as bad as all that.
Sure, it got a little bit scary at times?
And there was some danger involved?
but you know what?
Despite his frightening
and awful reputation,
Vash turned out to be
more of a regular guy?
than you would have thought.
Reality check, Meryl.
The attitude of yours gets all the oddball
jobs, working with dangerous slime.
It's great that you're
so competent and willing,
but if you keep risking
your life out there...
I'm afraid there's no way you'll
ever achieve womanly happiness.
Excuse me.
Is this social time, ladies and gentlemen?
Good morning.
It's nice to see you, Chief.
Meryl, will you please
step into my office?
Sir?
I have to what?
Millie? Millie? Where
are you? I'm out here.
Good morning, Meryl.
What have you gotten yourself into now?
Well, I'm being punished for coming
in late for work 20 times in a row.
Why do I expect her to change?
I'm dreaming.
Guess what?
We got another assignment today.
Vash the Stampede showed up in Little
Jersey, and we're the only ones qualified.
We leave right away. Yay!
Then it's really true.
Vash is still alive.
Doesn't that make you incredibly happy?
There's nothing to be happy about.
Our jobs are on the line here, Millie.
We have to stop him this time
before he stirs up trouble again.
Now, come on.
You're wasting time.
Let's get going.
Wait, hold on a second, Meryl.
Aren't you being a little hasty?
For crying out loud, if he's alive,
he could have at least mentioned it.
He probably gets a kick out of
making people bite his dust.
That bum.
Merrill!
I'll bring you back an
AAP bag as a souvenir.
See you later, Karen!
Oh, well. It's no use.
There she goes again.
I suppose there's just some girls
who need to risk their lives.
If you're dead, you don't
have to say anything,
but if you're alive, I would appreciate
if you fellas would say something.
I'll give you a lift.
Uh, gee.
Gee, bless you, mister.
Yeah, I am pretty damn happy to be alive.
Why is it that I always run into
so much trouble when you're around?
You're not a very
methodical person, are you?
Normally when you buy a used bike,
you're supposed to repair it, you know,
make sure it's in decent condition before
you decide to take it out and ride it.
Are you dissing my beautiful
shiny Angelina Tuvas?
Actually, I'm dissing you, not
your stupid broken motorcycle!
Come again, needle noggin?
Hey, who you calling needle noggin?
I say it's pretty darn obvious!
Now look what you've done, you idiot!
Oh, so now it's my fault, huh?
Shut up back there, or
I'll have to fool you out!
Well, is that me?
Yes, sir, we're really sorry.
All right, now where are you guys headed?
Kansas.
New Oregon.
Huh?
Uh, New Oregon?
We're going to the town with all the
disappearances in Southern Cornelia.
No, I want to go to New Oregon.
If you want to go to Kansas,
go there by yourself!
You're going to, sir!
I said, shut up, your turn!
Huh? We're sorry.
This place is really falling apart
Go over where we're from making
trouble as usual Then all of
a sudden this guy stepped in to
help Seemed like a pretty well
-meaning fella And unfortunately
this is what happened as a
result Once again he's poked his
nose into more trouble Honestly,
that man never learns Meryl!
I just found out where Vash
is and they said he's okay
Vash?
Yep,
the one and only humanoid
typhoon He carries the dubious
title of mankind's first
localized human disaster.
That's ridiculous.
When I saw him,
he was weeping and eating piles of
donuts at the same time, just like this.
Donuts are his favorite food.
It's really him?
I can't believe it.
This nutcase is actually
the legendary gunman?
So where'd you get your
information, Millie?
Over the satellite.
Everyone's talking about it.
The report said that he's headed for New
Oregon at a speed of 3,000 yards an hour.
Isn't that incredible?
He can move really fast.
That's a little more
information than I needed.
Yeah, I know.
And one of the locals was even running
around telling everyone to be careful.
You can't be serious.
The day before yesterday,
most of the Polo family went out of town,
leaving no one there but
the fourth son, Slater.
Also, I found there's a shuttle
that goes to New Oregon.
It's ideal.
A chance like this
doesn't come twice. I...
I don't know about this.
All right, I'll do it.
I think we all agree the Polo family can't
be allowed to have their way anymore.
Huh?
Aren't I right?
Right.
Well, sort of.
At least this time, we'll have Mr.
Rinald with us to back us up.
Yeah, that's true.
That settles it, then.
All right, gentlemen, this is it.
We'll meet here again at sunup tomorrow.
Shut up and listen up!
Today I'm going to school you people!
Today's lesson is about typhoons!
Since you probably don't know, here I go!
A typhoon is a little phenomenon
where the wind blows like
crazy and carries your houses
and tins off into the sky.
Her name is Jacqueline, and this lovely
young lady has come to wipe you out.
What's all this about, Mr.
Typhoon?
Are you expecting a relative
of yours sometime soon?
So, is that what a typhoon is?
A furious beauty who levels entire
cities without even a warning.
A beauty?
Sounds pretty tough.
Hey, by the way, who's picking
up the tab for this little food?
Me? Why me?
I was the one gracious enough
to give it to your stupid
whining and come all the
way out here to New Oregon.
Didn't ask you to do that.
Now listen up.
This town may look peaceful,
but things are likely to get
bloody around here at any time.
I don't know if you're aware of this,
but the Polo and Frieze
families are still quarreling!
over their rights to the satellite.
A girl who was a distant cousin of the
Frieze family was murdered in cold blood.
It's a high-stakes feud.
The more I think about it,
but I don't want this town to
turn into another little jersey.
Let's take off before it's destroyed.
Knock it off!
But doesn't that story get you upset?
Why do things like that have to happen?
It's not like it's anything new.
This kind of thing happens all the time.
Even the most peaceful
folk will take up arms if
someone happens to threaten
or kill a family member.
Bottom line is, we should go
before we get involved in this.
I've always had my suspicions
that you were no mere mortal,
but I never imagined
you were actually a cat.
Wait, what the hell am I saying?
Where is that idiot? Sir?
Altogether, your meal
comes to exactly $30.
Put it on my tab? No, thanks.
Rotten needle noggin.
Uh, Mr.
Slater, there's a hick outside
asking to be let in, sir.
Sir?
I'm not interested in any
beggars or job hunters.
Just send them away.
A friend of mine works here,
and I was in the neighborhood.
I just thought I'd drop
by to say hi to him.
Hey, I didn't say you could
come in here, street worm.
Who are you here to see?
His name is Max Simon.
That old codger actually has friends?
Go ahead, entertain him.
All right, thanks a lot.
I appreciate it. Bye.
Sure about this, boss?
Do I really have a choice?
He's a friend of Max's, and I'm
not about to start any trouble now.
This was a good idea.
We did the right thing to splurge
on a room in second class.
Yeah, the last time we were when
it is, it was full advantage.
The whole experience was ruined.
If we run into him in New Oregon,
things are gonna get real busy.
Let's enjoy the peace while it lasts.
I guess that means we're going to
get dragged into trouble again, huh?
Oh, my thunder!
Hands with the air and mouth shut.
He's better not trying anything funny.
You understand me?
Not an end!
I suggest you all behave
if you value your lives.
Make this easy on yourself and don't move.
I promise you won't be
harmed if you just cooperate.
You have a chance to stop this right
now and the law will be more lenient.
I gave up my life a
long time ago. Besides,
there's a damn good reason I'm doing
this, and I don't care what the cost is.
We've almost reached our destination.
Make sure you keep an eye on him.
Got it.
If she were alive, she'd be
about your age now, you know?
I'm not finished with the forecast.
Beat it, leave me alone.
I can see you haven't
changed a bit, old man.
Vash!
It's been a very long time.
What happened to the old snappy outfit?
I guess I kind of wore
it out on my last job
Well,
welcome back you are here on business or
just come to pick up Jacqueline's dress
Hmm.
Has it really been ten years
since your last visit Vash?
No, Marcy!
Kill anyone every day!
Where is he?
I want him!
Holy cow!
A Monsterian just crashed a sand
steamer into my exalted place of work!
I've heard of people falling asleep
at the wheel, but this is ridiculous!
Mr. F!
Pardon me, coming through.
Excuse me, lady.
Sorry about that.
Ooh, this is bad. Looks like a raid.
Of New Oregon, listen carefully.
The Freeze family has seized
the satellite facility.
The injustice we have suffered
at the hands of the greedy,
vicious Polos have left us with no choice.
We have but one demand.
Bring us the head of the Polo family.
We have a guest we think will
be of great interest to him.
Help me!
Somebody help me!
So that's how it is.
If our demands are not
met within three days,
I will not be able to
guarantee his safety.
The head of the family is in Neo-Colorado.
It's impossible.
He'll never make it
back within three days.
Are you going in?
You know me, Max.
It's just my nature.
I have to do it.
All right.
All we have to do is kill Polo, use
Jacqueline for cover, and make tracks.
Piece of cake.
Who's Jacqueline?
It's the name of the typhoon which is
heading for this town, and it's coming soon
He's talking about the
real storm kind of typhoon.
How in the world did
you mix that up Millie?
What were you thinking?
I feel so silly it
slipped my mind darn it.
I hate being wrong
Come on, let's get out of here Millie
I...
I saw White Angels.
They seem to have the
hostages under control.
He says we can do whatever we want
with the others, know what I mean?
Sounds good.
I say we go have some fun.
I just love party time.
You two should be ashamed
of yourselves. Huh? Huh?
Vash, amazing, are you
still doing things this way?
Uh, yeah.
What the hell?
Are you a polo bodyguard?
No, I'm not.
If you have a death wish,
gentlemen, try to take us down.
But before you do, you should know
that this man is Vash, the Stampede.
What'd you say?
Aw, come on, Max.
Can you at least act the part?
They'll chicken out and
run away and we won't
have to fight them do you really think so?
He's up there Benson?
There's no one to shoot here!
I'll take your finger off the trigger.
Yeah, you're right.
I'm sorry
What is it it's the gunman it's
fast to stampede he's coming our way
he's coming you saw him But why what
would vast stampede be doing here?
This is like a bad dream
enough calm down, huh?
rumors like this are
always exaggerated and
Even if he is the real thing he still
has to take that passage to get here.
It's the only way in Remember, it's
the reason we chose this location.
Oh, yeah.
He's here!
Total slaughter, total slaughter.
I won't leave a single man alive.
La-dee-da-dee-dae.
General sign.
An ocean of blood.
Let's begin the killing time!
He's singing?
God, what horrible lyrics!
Stay right where you are Huh?
He's just trying to scare you.
I knew it wouldn't work!
Hey, can I ask you something? Yeah, what?
Would you prefer to call off our
little game like a sensible adult?
Or would you rather get injured
and be out of the game for good?
How about a new game?
I'll answer your question
with another question.
Now that I'll play, do you
want a belly full of lead?
Oh, what a shame.
A negotiations breakdown.
Get out of my way!
What?
Shit, this guy can't be for real!
Hey, Mr. Renowned!
He's...
gone!
Alright, that's it.
The fight is over.
It's time for you to let
go of the hostage now.
Actually, I'm grateful to you.
Now that that's out of the
way, I'm gonna get to kill him.
I'll whack you, mister.
What could possibly give you the
right to do something like that?
Now, come on.
Give the guy a break.
Forget it!
How would you knock it off?
He killed her!
This bastard killed her!
He killed my daughter, and he's gonna die!
He's gonna pay for her
death with his life!
He can't!
We're nothing like God.
Not only do we have limited powers,
we sometimes are driven to
become the devil himself.
What's your answer this time?
That was my daughter.
My daughter.
This is horrible.
Dear God, Donahue.
I know she's related to the freeze,
but she had nothing to do with it.
I'll make it fast.
Once I've finished here, you
can hand me over to the sheriff?
or even the cavalry.
Don't do it! Please!
I don't wanna die.
Forgive me.
Forgive me, please.
I'm sorry.
How dare you beg for your life?
What about my daughter begging for hers?
When I saw what you did
to my little Eileen,
my Eileen, no human being
could do such an evil thing.
You people, you people aren't
human, and you all need to die!
Don't let me die! Stop! Stop!
Oh, stop, please!
Justice at last.
Donut, it's wrong.
I must avenge her.
Get off!
What the hell do you know about this?
You can never understand how I feel!
I don't want your help.
That got me!
Daddy!
How many times did my
daughter scream for her daddy?
How many times?!
Don't take this man's life!
Don't kill him, please! Please!
Please don't shoot him!
Don't do it!
I'm begging you!
This is so strange, Eileen.
I can't shoot him.
Why can't I do it?
I want to avenge you.
Why can't I do it? He should die!
Oh, thank goodness. Huh? It's nothing.
I'm just glad it's over now.
I think it would be a good
idea to get both of them as
far away from here as we can
before the cavalry arrives.
Stretch over here!
The shootout which began late
this afternoon was brought
to a safe conclusion with one
swift charge of the cavalry.
The twelve idiots who were held
hostage, myself included, were freed.
For an incident involving the humanoid
typhoon, the damage wasn't that bad.
The day after tomorrow, a real
typhoon is coming to town.
Be very, very careful, boys and girls.
Go easy on the nice guy stuff, okay?
You gotta start taking care of yourself.
Luck and persistence won't work forever.
So long.
Long time no see. Yeah.
I have now found him.
I will total everything, so my
conclusion will then be final.
There is no doubt.
Vash the Stampede has
begun to move, Mr. Legato.
The wind is in the future.
The sun is in the future.
The sun is in the future. As we can't
hold
the light.
I can't wait to
see the next day.
I can't wait to see the future.
In times of hardship,
in times of sadness, there is a place
the Traveler can let his mind return to,
home.
I still don't know what kind of a past the
Traveler abandoned when
he left his home behind.
I still don't know what
kind of sorrow he bears,
but the Traveler can keep walking forward,
because he has something which sustains
him, a place which accepts him.
He can walk forward, step by careful step.